Guide to the Richard Foster Jones Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Richard Foster Jones papers
1909-1965
SC0118
Jones, Richard Foster, 1886-1965.
1 Linear feet
Collection contains manuscripts dating from his period at Stanford as well as papers from his student days at Cornell (1909-1918) and correspondence written during his service as Dean of Graduate Studies at Washington University (1943-1945). Also included are personal business papers and correspondence from 1945-1965.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of anonymous, 1972.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Professor of English at Stanford (1945-1952) and founder of the Stanford Creative Writing Center.
Description of the Collection
Collection contains manuscripts dating from his period at Stanford as well as papers from his student days at Cornell (1909-1918) and correspondence written during his service as Dean of Graduate Studies at Washington University (1943-1945). Also included are personal business papers and correspondence from 1945-1965.
Access Terms
Jones, Richard Foster, 1886-1965.; Stanford University. Department of English. Faculty.; Manuscripts (for publication).
Collection Contents
- Papers
  - Typescript – "The Rhetoric of Science in England of the Mid-seventeenth Century" (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Research notes for "The Rhetoric of Science in England of the Mid-seventeenth Century" (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Research notes for "The Rhetoric of Science in England of the Mid-seventeenth Century" (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Research notes for "The Rhetoric of Science in England of the Mid-seventeenth Century"; and Early papers written while a student at Columbia (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "Poetry" – typed (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "Literary Scholarship in an Atomic Age" – typed (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - "Browning and the Greek Drama" – holograph (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "Racine and the English Critics of the Neoclassical Period" – typed (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "Bacon and the Idea of Science" – typed (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - "Swift's Fight Against Pedantry" – typed (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - "Greek Lyric Poetry in the Elizabethan Lyric" – holograph (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - "Wordsworth's Characters" – holograph (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - "Dialogue to Pantomime" and "In Imitation of Dobson" – holographs (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - "Charlotte Hallaran Jones – a Sketch" by Kate E. White. A biography of Jones' mother, 2 copies (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Pamphlet – "By Appointment of His Majesty, Biographer of Samuel Johnson, L.L.D." by James M. Osborn (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Research notes for a book on language (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Research notes from Robert Ferguson's "The Interest of Reason in Religion, 1675" – holograph and type copies (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Research notes – miscellaneous and unsorted, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Bibliography of Jones' published writings, 1919-1947; Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Incoming correspondence from U. S. Armed Services, 1917-1918 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Aug. 14, 1943 – June 30, 1945, written when Dean of Graduate Studies, Washington University (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence with Kenneth Brown, estate manager, 1948-1961 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous academic papers; includes degrees, manuscript, class registration booklets (1909-1918), and newspaper reviews. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous financial papers, includes business and tax receipts, medical expenses, and insurance correspondence, 1945-56 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Tax files and other personal business correspondence, Feb. – Oct. 1965 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous financial papers, 1948-1961 (Box 3, Folder 1)